## **Keen Renzo Ballon**

Email: keenballon@gmail.com	LinkedIn: Keen Ballon
SUMMARY	
Cloud engineer with developer and QA Automation experience. Geared towards making my co-workers' development experience easier, I've focused on making the development pipeline automated and setting up cloud infra which ensured more time for developer action.	
<ul> <li>Specific skills include:</li> <li>Kubernetes (EKS) and Docker</li> <li>AWS and GCP</li> <li>Bash Scripting and CI/CD Automation</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Python and NodeJS</li> <li>Git, Bitbucket, and GitLab</li> <li>Agile Methodology (Scrum)</li> </ul>
WORK EXPERIENCE	
<ul> <li>Media Meter Inc.   Junior Cloud Engineer (July 2024 - Present)</li> <li>Reduced cloud infra costs by approximately 40% thru optimization of EKS EC2 instances</li> <li>Established pipelines allowing developers to easily deploy by themselves cutting development overhead.</li> <li>Enabled observability through DataDog and NewRelic</li> <li>Maintained our cloud and on-premise Kubernetes platform (EKS)</li> <li>Lessened repetitive nodegroup provision thru CloudFormation as IaC</li> </ul>	
Achieve Without Borders Inc.  Junior Full Stack Developer (September 2022 - July 2024)  Developed features and API endpoints for different sub-projects in an e-commerce app using different technologies (Flutter and Javascript).  Developed customized Python solutions using Odoo framework  Suggested solution for image requests that reduced latency from 100 - 500ms to 10-30ms.  Support client's specific data needs and database scraping tasks with custom made scripts providing information for business targets.  Allowed any developer to deploy to different environments due to establishment of automated CI/CD pipelines for different sub-projects, and reduced deployment time from 1hr and 30 mins to 30 mins at most.  Performed systems administration, provision, and monitoring on development and production servers.  QA Automation Engineer (February 2022 - September 2022)  Wrote programmatic test scripts extending Cypress test functionalities which also made the test process startup significantly faster to nearly 50% (15 seconds to 7.5 seconds)  Became a reference person for questions and queries regarding Cypress Testing.  Introduced DevOps pipeline changes in order to lessen overall testing time through strategic testing.  Recommended development approaches to a problem making tests for the feature possible.  Solutions Engineering Intern (December 2021 - February 2022)  Immersed on different roles in an Agile software development team thru assigned tasks related to: Development, QA, Business Analyst  Wrote Automation Test Scripts to support the testing initiatives of the project.  Addressed broken tests and improved them to be more change resilient  Previously identified impediments in testing were overcome as I created algorithms to solve them.	
EDUCATION	
De La Salle Araneta University - (2018 -2022)	

**PROJECTS** 

Portfolio and Blog Page - Github Link | Live Link

BS Computer Engineering : GWA of 3.49

## Tech Stack: React | Gatsby.js | Strapi (CMS) | Docker

- Using GitHub Actions triggered with every commit I am able to have a CD pipeline which deploys to Netlify as a website host for my portfolio project and a blog documentation of my journey.
- There is a dockerized version when I tried to learn about self-hosting on my own private server.

## Resume Page - Github Link | Live Link

## Tech Stack: AWS | Linux | Terraform | Docker | Nginx

• My full unabridged HTML version of my resume. Used Terraform to build the AWS cloud infrastructure which will contain the downloadable resume in AWS S3. Optional to run on docker build of NGINX to serve the content and put on AWS.